Name: Kondakamarla Kareemulla Mobile:+91 9740151271 e-mail:kareemulla380@gmail.com

# **Personal Summary**

Driven Retail Manager & HR co-ordinator with over 15 years' experience in the retail industry. Proven track record of success, including managing the top performing store in the region. I intend to take a challenging career with a leading organization, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential. Willing to work as a team player in an innovative, competitive and challenging environment.

Educational Qualifications		
Course/Degree	<u>Institute</u>	<u>Board</u>
S.S.C	ZPP High School	Board of Secondary Education, Andhra Pradesh
HSC	BT College	Board of Intermediate, Andhra Pradesh
Bachelor of Arts	Adarsh Vishwa Vidyalaya	Board of Degree, Andhra Pradesh

# **Experience Summary**

As a retail coordinator I coordinate with Human resources overseas issue related to employment, compensation, labour negotiation, and employee relation. Their work is often focused on improving HR policies, process, and practices, and recommending changes to HR management. To ensure efficient operation, I perform a substantial amount of research, data analysis, and reporting as it relates to employee productivity.

# **Retail Experience**

# Worked as a HR Co-Ordinator at Landmark Arabia from Apr 2012 to Sep 2018

## **Key Responsibilities:**

- Assisting with day to day operations of the HR functions and duties.
- Compiling and update employee records (hard and soft copies)
- Process documentation and prepare reports relating to personnel activities (staffing, recruitment, training, grievances, performance evaluations etc)
- Coordinate HR projects (meetings, training, surveys etc) and take minutes
- Deal with employee requests regarding human resources issues, rules, and regulations
- Facilitating human resources process. Administering employee health and welfare plans.
- Acting as liaison between employee and organisation. Resolving benefit-related problems.
- Ensuring the effective utilization of plans related to HR programs and services.
- Administering health and welfare plans, including enrolments, changes, and terminations.
- Answering employee requests and questions. Assisting with new employee hiring process.
- Reconciling benefit statements.
- Conducting audit of payroll, benefits, and other HR programs, and recommending corrective actions.
- Assisting with the performance review and termination process.
- Assisting with the recruitment and interview process.
- Handling backend operations work & assisting third party vendor related queries.
- Administrative support for all data entry on daily basis with MS Excel.

# Landmark Arabia as Store Manager from Mar 2009 to Mar 2012

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Maintains the stability and reputation of the store by complying with legal requirements.
- Manpower Planning Maintains store staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees.
- Maintains store staff job results by coaching, counselling, and disciplining employees; planning, monitoring, and appraising job results
- **Budget management** Achieves financial objectives by preparing an annual budget; scheduling expenditures; analysing variances; initiating corrective actions
- **Inventory Management** –Ensures availability of merchandise and services by approving contracts maintaining inventories.
- Sale Objective Setting up ways to achieve the Sales target of a particular department
- **Customer Service** Providing 100% customer service to everyone and also understand their preference and buying pattern
- **Floor Standards** Setting up the department as VM(Visual Merchandising) standards i.e. Colour blocking, Style Blocking, Size Blocking, Paper Stacking and cleanliness of the floor
- Completes store operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees; following up on work results.
- Comparing a growth report and keeping track on LFL year sale.

# Landmark Arabia (Assistant Store Manager) 2006 to 2009

# Landmark Arabia (sales Associate) 2003 to 2006

# **Competencies & Technical Skills**

- VM merchandising Displaying good team-work skills
- Providing training and induction to new employees
- MS-Office: Word, Excel.
- SIM, backend work, handling third party vendor related queries.

# **Career Highlights**

- Good command over Windows operating systems
- Strong grounding in basic Computer fundamentals and Type writing
- Highly motivated and quick to adopt to new tasks
- Good communication and interpolated skills
- Good leadership qualities and highly self-motivated and confident

### **Personal Details**

Name : Kondakamarla Kareemulla

Date of Birth : 09/03/1975 Nationality : Indian

Languages known : English, Arabic, Hindi, Telugu, and Urdu Present Address : No. 1, 1st floor, Opp. Jamia Masjid

Bazaar street, Halasuru, Bangalore - 560008

Declaration: I here by declare that the information and particulars given are true & correct to the best of my knowledge & belief.

Date:

Place: Bangalore (Kareemulla.K)